Guide to the The Inquiry Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
The Inquiry Papers
1915-1921
MS 8
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
18
(35 boxes, 4 folios)
Correspondence, organizational records, reports containing historical and statistical material, maps, and other papers of The Inquiry, a group of experts assembled at the request of President Wilson to collect and collate data in preparation for a peace conference following World War I. Members of The Inquiry included Edward House, Sidney Mezes, Isaiah Bowman, Charles Seymour, David H. Miller, Walter Lippmann, James T. Shotwell, and Clive Day.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Part of the collection was transferred from House Papers MS 466, and the remainder was the gift of the American Geographic Society in 1961.
Arrangement
Arranged in six series and oversized: I. Correspondence, 1918-1919, II. Records Regarding Administrative Matters, 1917-1919, undated, III. Reports and Studies, 1917-1920, undated, IV. Abstracts, Precis, Notes, 1902-1918, undated, V. Printed Materials, 1913-1927, undated, VI. Photographs and Maps, 1915-1918, undated.
Scope and Contents
As was noted by Stephen Helton in his introduction to the National Archives' Records of the American Commission to Negotiate Peace (Preliminary Inventories, No. 89; Washington: 1955), in the fall of 1917, following the declaration of war against Germany,
Col. E. M. House, at the request of President Wilson, began to assemble in New York a group of experts to collect and collate data on geographical, ethnological, historical, economic, and political problems of Europe and other areas of the world in preparation for the peace conference, which should follow World War I. This group of experts, called 'The Inquiry,' was under the direction first of Sidney E. Mezes and later of Isaiah Bowman. At the time of its greatest development it consisted of 18 divisions, 11 of which dealt with special problems of particular areas or regions. Its staff was made up largely of professors recruited from American universities and colleges. The Inquiry made a number of investigations; …and in 1918 it assembled a large quantity of material on national boundaries. In December 1918 The Inquiry ceased to be an independent body and was absorbed into the Division of Territorial, Economic, and Political Intelligence of the American Commission to Negotiate Peace.*
The Yale Inquiry Papers are an amalgamation of two separate collections: (a) a relatively small amount of material, dealing directly with The Inquiry, which Charles Seymour (the first curator of the House Collection) assembled from amongst his own papers and those of Colonel House and Clive Day and rearranged under an artificial "Inquiry" subheading; and (b) the much larger set of bona fide Inquiry "office records," left originally under the care of the American Geographical Society (The Inquiry's first "home") which were given to the Yale Library in 1961 in honor of President Seymour's 75th birthday.
The bulk of The Inquiry's records are housed in the National Archives, where they form part of Record Group 256 ("Records of the American Commission to Negotiate Peace"), whose contents are described in the Preliminary Inventory list [No. 89] mentioned above. The Yale Inquiry Papers consist to a considerable extent of duplicate material (roughly 12 cubic feet of material compared to 85 cubic feet housed in the National Archives); and even the strongest categories (Special Reports and Studies and Maps) are far from complete.
The Yale Inquiry Papers are arranged in six major series, which are described in greater detail in the pages that follow:
Series I. General Correspondence. (2 boxes) Primarily 'inter-office' correspondence from (or to) Clive Day and Charles Seymour, (1918-1919).
Series II. Records Regarding Administrative Matters. (1 box) The most significant items are Douglas Johnson's letters describing his special mission to England and France in the spring of 1918; and various "progress reports" from Sidney Mezes, Isaiah Bowman, and David Hunter Miller to Colonel House.
Series III. Reports and Studies. (23 boxes) The bulk of these reports deal with specific problems (and sub-divisions) of the Austro-Hungarian and Ottoman Empires; the Balkans; Alsace-Lorraine; the Adriatic question; Poland; India, and German colonies in Africa. (An "Index of Authors" is appended.)
Series IV. Abstracts, Precis, Notes. (5 boxes) Various notes and miscellaneous research materials used primarily by Charles Seymour and Clive Day in their studies on Austria-Hungary and the Balkans.
Series V. Printed Materials. (1 box) Ten miscellaneous items.
Series VI. Maps and Photographs (4 folios and 3 boxes) Maps: [Consult Reference Archivist. The reprocessing and rearrangement of this section of the Yale Inquiry Papers has not been completed.]; Photographs: See page 73
* See also Lawrence Gelfand, The Inquiry: American Preparations for Peace, 1917-1919 [New Haven: 1963]; and Harold B. Whitemen (ed.), Charles Seymour's Letters from the Paris Peace Conference [New Haven: 1965]. Much additional information will undoubtedly emerge from Arthur Walworth's forthcoming study on American diplomacy at the peace conference; volumes VI and VII of Arthur Link's biography of Woodrow Wilson; the pertinent volumes of The Papers of Woodrow Wilson, and Charles Neu's projected full scale biography of Colonel House.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Appendix
INDEX OF AUTHORS (Series III) Abbott, J. F. See: Japan
Andrews, A. I. See: Caucasus, Transcaucasus
Andrews, G. F. See: France
Andrus, A. N. See: Turkey
Arctowski, H. See: Poland (11)
Armstrong, E. C. See: Alsace-Lorraine
Beam, J. N. See: Turkey
Beer, G. L. See: Africa (3), Egypt, Middle Africa
Bell, H. W. See: Turkey (2)
Birge, J. K. See: Turkey
Blakeslee, G. H. See: Germany
Blythe, S. G. See: China
Bonner, C. See: India
Bonney [A. L. ?] See: Argentina
Bonright, J. C. See: Turkey
de Booy, T. See: Colombia
Brailsford, H. N. See: Turkey
Breasted, J. A. See: Turkey
Bruere, H. See: Latin America
Butler, H. C. See: Turkey
Byrne, E. H. See: Syria, Turkey
Campbell, O. J. See: Turkey (3), Zionism
Chamberlain, J. P. See: Belgium
Chekrezi, C. A. See: Albania
Churchill, W. See: Germany
Clark, V. See: Germany
Collier, W. M. See: Spain
Cook, W. L. See: Colombia
Coolidge, A. C. See: Macedonia
Davison, E. F. See: Great Britain
Day, Clive See: Austria-Hungary (5), Balkans (2), Belgium, Bohemia, Dutch East Indies, Economic Topics, France, Germany, Poland, Russia
Dennis, A. L. P. See: Turkey
Dickerman, S. O. See: Turkey (2)
Dixon, R. B. See: Central Asia, Crimean Peninsula, Russia, Turkestan (3)
Dodd, W. E. See: Monroe Doctrine (2)
Dominian, L. See: Arab Problem, Arabia, Asia, Mohammedan World, Saloniki, Turkey
Evans, A. P. See: Austria-Hungary (2)
Fairchild, F. R. See: Public Debts (2)
Fay, S. B. See: Baltic Provinces, Lettland
Fenwick, C. G. See: States Less Than Sovereign
Flournoy, F. R. See: Lithuania
Frost, A. C. See: Algeria
Fuller, G. P. See: Great Britain
Golder, F. A. See: Baltic Provinces, Don Province, Lithuania (4), Siberia, Ukraine (2)
Goldman, H. See: Alsace-Lorraine
Gray, L. H. See: Caucasus, Dalmatia, Danube, Eastern Europe, Spitzbergen
Gulbenkian, G. See: Turkey
Hall, W. H. See: Turkey
Hannah, I. C. See: South Africa
Hardy, O. See: Colombia, Peru
Harris, N. D. See: Tibet
Haskins, C. H. See: Alsace-Lorraine, Belgium
Hitchcock, F. C. See: China
Hobbs, W. H. See: Rivers as International Boundaries, Turkey, Asiastic
Holderer, George B. See: Brazil
Hopkins, Manley O. See: Latin America
Hornbeck, S. K. See: China (3), Russia
Howe, Frederic C. See: Mediterranean
Hrdlicka, A. See: Russia
Hudson, M. O. See: Freedom of the Seas
Hunter, Campbell W. See: Argentina
Hurban, V. S. See: Czechs
Jackson, A. V. W. See: Persia (3)
Jackson, T. G. See: Dalmatia
Jacoby, J. H. See: Alsace-Lorraine
Jefferson, M. See: Bohemia, Russia
Jewell, John F. See: Mozambique
Johnson, D. See: Rumania
Jones, Mrs. Robert W. See: Nigeria
Joseph, S. See: Immigration
Kenyon, D. See: India (10)
Kerner, Robert J. See: Austria-Hungary (6), Bohemia, Czechs (2), Near Eastern Question, Yugoslavia (2)
Krehbiel, E. B. See: Alsace-Lorraine (2), Belgium
Larsen, H. A. See: Slesvig
Lavis, F. See: China
Le Plae, E. V. See: Belgian Congo
Lippmann, Walter See: Economic Penetration, International Law
Lord, R. H. See: Eastern Europe, Poland (7)
Lowell, A. L. See: League of Nations
Lunt, W. E. See: Italy
Lybyer, A. H. See: Yugoslavia
McGuire, C. E. See: Latin America
Magie, D. See: Assyrian Christians, Syria, Turkey (4)
Marsh, M. G. See: Brussels Sugar Convention, Merchant Marine
Masaryk, T. G. See: Pan-Germanism
Miller, David Hunter See: International Tariff Court, Law of the Air
Milmore, L. See: Aaland
Monroe, P. See: Albania, Austria-Hungary, Educational Reforms, Japan, Prussian School Laws, Russia, Turkey (2)
Monroe, W. S. See: Albania (2), Balkans (6), Danube (2), Macedonia (3), Petrograd Protocol, Yugoslavia
Moon, P. T. See: Africa, Germany
Morgan, W. T. See: Italy (2)
Morison, S. E. See: Finland
Morris, F. B. See: Brazil, Paraguay, the Chaco
Munro, D. C. See: Mesopotamia, Turkey (2), Turkey, Asiatic
Munro, H. F. See: Berlin Congress
Murphy, G. See: South Africa
McBride, G. M. See: Argentina
Newell, F. H. See: Turkey, Asiatic
Noli, F. S. See: Albania
Notestein, W. See: Alsace-Lorraine (6)
Oakley, H. S. See: Freedom of the Seas
Peet, W. W. See: Turkey
Pitkin, W. H. See: Far Eastern Policy, Japan (3)
Porter, H. See: Turkey
Putney, A. H. See: Austria-Hungary, Poland
Reed, W. H. See: Bessarabia, Rumania (2)
Riggs, H. H. See: Turkey (2)
Robertson, W. Henry See: Argentina
Romer, E. See: Poland
Rubinow, I. M. See: Russia (4)
Savic, V. R. See: Yugoslavia
Scudder [Miss] See: Ethnic Groups
Semple, E. C. See: Austria-Hungary, Mesopotamia, Turkey, Asiatic (2)
Seymour, Charles See: Austria-Hungary (14), Cyprus, Spitzbergen, Yugoslavia (2)
Shaw, E. W. See: Mexico
Shipman, H. R. See: Turkey
Shotwell, J. T. See: Alsace-Lorraine, Turkey, Asiatic
Slosson, P. W. See: Australasia, New Zealand, Russia, Samoa
Smith, D. E. See: International Currency
Smith, M. See: Germany
Smith, W. R. See: Opium Problem
Sonnichsen, A. See: Macedonia
Southard, A. E. See: Abyssinia
Steefel, L. D. See: Luxemburg, Slesvig
Stozek, J. See: Alsace-Lorraine
Szlupas, J. See: Lithuania
Taussig, F. W. See: Colonial Tariffs, United States International Commercial Policy
Thomas, W. I. See: Nationalism
Torrey, C. C. See: Arabia
Updegraff, R. See: Alsace-Lorraine (2)
Veblen, T. B. See: Economic Penetration
Vincent, J. M. See: Turkey (2)
Watson, A. G. See: Aden
Westermann, W. L. See: Turkey (3)
White, J. C. See: Balkans
Williams, M. O. See: Czechs
Willoughby, W. W. See: States Less Than Sovereign
Winston, A. P. See: China (5), Japan
Wood, John Q. See: Azores
Wrighley, G. M. See: Africa (4)
Znanciecki, F. See: Poland (3)
Zowski, S. J. See: Poland (5), Vistula
Emigration and immigration; Self-determination, National; World War, 1914-1918; Latin America; United States -- Foreign relations; Maps; Photoprints; Adams, James Truslow, 1878-1949; Auchincloss, Gordon, 1886-1943; Beer, George Louis, 1872-1920; Bowman, Isaiah, 1878-1950; Brailsford, Henry Noel, 1873-1958; Breasted, James Henry, 1865-1935; Campbell, Oscar James, 1879-1970; Coolidge, Archibald Cary, 1866-1928; Cross, Wilbur L. (Wilbur Lucius), 1862-1948; Davison, Frederick Trubee, 1896-1974; Day, Clive, 1871-1951; Dodd, William E. (William Edward), 1869-1940; Domeratzky, Louis, 1881-; Dominian, Leon, 1880-1935; Duggan, Stephen, 1870-1950; Farnam, Henry W. (Henry Walcott), 1853-1933; Fay, Sidney Bradshaw, 1876-1967; Ferguson, William Scott, 1875-1954; Furniss, Edgar S. (Edgar Stevenson), 1890-1972; Hadley, Arthur Twining, 1856-1930; Haskins, Charles Homer, 1870-1937; Hayes, Carlton J. H. (Carlton Joseph Huntley), 1882-1964; Hocking, William Ernest, 1873-1966; Hornbeck, Stanley Kuhl, 1883-1966; House, Edward Mandell, 1858-1938; Hrdlička, Aleš, 1869-1943; Jefferson, Mark, 1863-1949; Jones, Frederick Scheetz, 1862-1944; Kerner, Robert Joseph, 1887-1956; Lansing, Robert, 1864-1928; Lewis, Charlton Miner, 1866-1923; Lippmann, Walter, 1889-1974; Lord, Robert Howard, 1885-1954; Lybyer, Albert Howe, 1876-1949; Mezes, Sidney Edward, 1863-1931; Miller, David Hunter, 1875-1961; Monroe, W. S. (Will Seymour), 1863-1939; Morison, Samuel Eliot, 1887-1976; Notestein, Wallace, 1878-1969; Polk, Frank Lyon, 1871-1943; Seymour, Charles, 1885-1963; Shotwell, James T., 1874-1965; Simkhovitch, Vladimir G. (Vladimir Gregorievitch), 1874-1959; Slosson, Preston W. (Preston William), 1892-1984; Stokes, Anson Phelps, 1874-1958; Taussig, F. W. (Frank William), 1859-1940; Thorpe, M. H. (Merle Harold), 1879-1955; Tinker, Chauncey Brewster, 1876-1963; Veblen, Thorstein, 1857-1929; Warburg, Paul M. (Paul Moritz), 1868-1932; Westermann, William Linn, 1873-1954; Wilbur, Ray L. (Ray Lyman), 1875-1949; Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924; Paris Peace Conference. United States Territorial Section ( 1919-1920. United States Territorial Section) -- 1919-1920
- Correspondence, 1918-1919; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains letters to and from certain members of The Inquiry staff (primarily Clive Day and Charles Seymour, but also Sidney E. Mezes, Isaiah Bowman, David Hunter Miller, and a few others), as well as directives from State Department officials intimately connected with the work of The Inquiry (Robert Lansing, Frank L. Polk, Gordon Auchincloss).
  Series I is subdivided as follows (individual folders are arranged alphabetically by correspondent): (a) Letters to or from Clive Day; (b) Letters to or from Charles Seymour; (c) Letters to or from Isaiah Bowman; (d) Letters to or from Sidney E. Mezes; (e) Letters to or from Gordon Auchincloss; (f) Miscellaneous letters.
  The number in parentheses following each correspondent's name records the number of documents in the folder.
  - Clive Day
    - Adams, James (1) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Amberton, Clare (4) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Babcock, Kendric C. (2) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Baker, O. E. (5) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Balkan Committee (7) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Re: Richmond Brooks Barrett (9) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Bell, H. W. (2) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Blegen, Carl (1) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Bosseux, Lucie (1) (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Bowman, Isaiah (38) (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Buck, Norman S. (3) (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Burk, Thomas (3) (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Chekrezi, Constantin A. (2) (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Cross, Wilbur L. (2) (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Denovan, R. (1) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - "Diary Letters" (4) (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Domeratsky, Louis (5) (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Duggan, Stephen P. (2) (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Fairchild, F. R. (1) (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Farnham, Henry W. (4) (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Fast, Louisa (2) (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Federal Adding Machine Corporation (2) (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Ferguson, W. S. (23) (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Fairchild, Fred R. (1) (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Frary, D. P. (1) (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Fuller, Grace P. (7) (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Furniss, E. S. (1) (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Hadley, Arthur T. (3) (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Hague, Florence A. (1) (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Haskins, Charles H. (5) (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Hayes, Carlton J. H. (1) (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Hocking, W. E. (1) (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Hornbeck, Stanley J. (1) (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Irvin, Fannie (2) (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Jefferson, Mark (6) (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Johnson, Douglas (1) (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Jones, Frederick S. (4) (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Keogh, Andrew (6) (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Klein, David L. (2) (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Lamm, Lawrence W. (2) (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Lansing, Robert (2) (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Larson, Laurence M. (4) (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Lewis, Charlton M. (1) (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Lewis, Mary B. (2) (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Lippmann, Walter (17) (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Longmans, Green and Company (1) (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Lord, Robert H. (10) (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Lybyer, Albert H. (3) (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - [Bureau of] Manufactures (1) (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Mathes (?) (1) (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Mc Neill, C. E. (1) (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Mezes, Sidney E. (5) (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Monroe, Will S. (1) (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Morgan, Charles S. (1) (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Morison, S. E. (2) (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - New Haven Bank (1) (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Nichols, W. W. (1) (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Noyes, George R. (3) (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Page, Thomas Walker (3) (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Parmelee, Julius (2) (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Paton, Jean (2) (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Peieff, Nicholas (1) (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Putnam, Ruth (13) (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Robb, J. D. (1) (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Roorbach, G. B. (2) (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Sack, A. J. (1) (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Seymour, Charles (19) (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Shotwell, J. T. (5) (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Shufeldt, Margaret D. (2) (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Simkhovitch, Vladimir (2) (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - State Museum, University of the State of New York (1) (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Stine, O. C. (25) (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Stokes, Anson Phelps (1) (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Storck, John (1) (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Sweeney, Charles R. (5) (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Thorpe, Merle (2) (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - Tinker, Chauncey B. (1) (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - War Camp Community Service (2) (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Westermann, W. L. (1) (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - Wilson, Woodrow (3) (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - Woodruff, Rollin S. (3) (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - Wright, Helen (3) (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Yale Daily News (2) (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - Young, Allyn A. (19) (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Charles Seymour
    - Adams, G. B. (1) (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Adams, James T. (2) (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Allen, A. F. (1) (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Baker, O. E. (2) (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Bishop, Lottie G. (1) (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Bowman, Isaiah (19) (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Carter, John (1) (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Committee on Public Information (1) (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Davison, F. Trubee (3) (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Day, Mrs. George Parmly (1) (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Esberg, A. I. (1) (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Fisher, Samuel H. (3) (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Gibbons, F (C. A. Nichols Company) (2) (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - Hadley, Morris (1) (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Kerner, Robert J. (4) (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - Kendall, W. Sergeant (1) (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - Lippmann, Walter (3) (Box 2, Folder 101)
    - Miller, D. Hunter (1) (Box 2, Folder 102)
    - Moore, Charles Everitt (1) (Box 2, Folder 103)
    - Morrell, Norman B. (2) (Box 2, Folder 104)
    - Murtfeldt, W. Scott (1) (Box 2, Folder 105)
    - Pierre, G. O. (1) (Box 2, Folder 106)
    - Stokes, Anson Phelps (1) (Box 2, Folder 107)
    - Walcott, F. C. (1) (Box 2, Folder 108)
    - Watkins, T. H. (2) (Box 2, Folder 109)
    - Wilson, E. G. (1) (Box 2, Folder 110)
    - Witzmann, Henry (1) (Box 2, Folder 111)
    - Re: Irving Marks (1) (Box 2, Folder 112)
    - Young, Allyn A. (1) (Box 2, Folder 113)
  - Isaiah Bowman
    - Billy, Edouard de (1) (Box 2, Folder 114)
    - Cotton, Joseph (1) (Box 2, Folder 114a)
    - [Division Chiefs] (1) (Box 2, Folder 115)
    - House, E. M. (6) (Box 2, Folder 116)
    - Jefferson, Mark (1) (Box 2, Folder 117)
    - Jones, Frederick S. (1) (Box 2, Folder 118)
    - Kerner, [Robert J.?] (1) (Box 2, Folder 119)
    - Lippmann, Walter (1) (Box 2, Folder 120)
    - Miller, David Hunter (1) (Box 2, Folder 121)
    - B. F. Stevens and Brown (2) (Box 2, Folder 122)
    - Willis, Bailey (2) (Box 2, Folder 123)
  - Sidney E. Mezes
    - Bowman, Isaiah (2) (Box 2, Folder 124)
    - Denovan, R. (1) (Box 2, Folder 125)
    - Haynsworth, M. Francis (1) (Box 2, Folder 126)
    - House, E. M. (10) (Box 2, Folder 127)
    - Johnson, Douglas (2) (Box 2, Folder 128)
    - Lambie, J. E. (1) (Box 2, Folder 129)
    - Lansing, Robert (5) (Box 2, Folder 130)
    - Lippmann, Walter (1) (Box 2, Folder 131)
    - Metaxa, John N. (1) (Box 2, Folder 132)
    - Miller, David Hunter (2) (Box 2, Folder 133)
    - Munro, D. C. (1) (Box 2, Folder 134)
    - Phillips, William (1) (Box 2, Folder 135)
    - Taussig, F. W. (1) (Box 2, Folder 136)
    - Young, Allyn A. (1) (Box 2, Folder 137)
  - Gordon Auchincloss
    - Barclay, Colville (1) (Box 2, Folder 138)
    - Billy, Edouard de (1) (Box 2, Folder 139)
    - Bowman, Isaiah (38) (Box 2, Folder 140)
    - Gilbert, Walter (1) (Box 2, Folder 141)
    - Lippmann, Walter (3) (Box 2, Folder 142)
    - Mezes, Sidney E. (36) (Box 2, Folder 143)
    - Miller, David Hunter (8) (Box 2, Folder 144)
    - Redfield, William C. (1) (Box 2, Folder 145)
    - Storck, John (1) (Box 2, Folder 146)
    - Warburg, Paul M. (1) (Box 2, Folder 147)
    - Wilbur, Ray Lyman (1) (Box 2, Folder 148)
  - Miscellaneous Letters
    - Keogh, Andrew -- Farnum, J. L. (1) (Box 2, Folder 149)
    - Lambie, J. E. -- House, E. M. (1) (Box 2, Folder 150)
    - Lansing, Robert -- Woodward, Robert S. (3) (Box 2, Folder 151)
    - Miller, David Hunter -- Church, Harriet J. (6) (Box 2, Folder 152)
    - Miller, David Hunter -- House, E. M. (8) (Box 2, Folder 153)
    - Miller, David Hunter -- Lansing, Robert (1) (Box 2, Folder 154)
    - Miller, David Hunter -- Whitehouse, Remsen (1) (Box 2, Folder 155)
    - Polk, Frank L. -- Johnson, D. W. (2) (Box 2, Folder 156)
    - Polk, Frank L. -- Mezes, Sidney E. (5) (Box 2, Folder 157)
    - Polk, Frank L. -- Miller, David Hunter (1) (Box 2, Folder 158)
    - American Geographical Society (10) (Box 2, Folder 158A)
- Records Regarding Administrative Matters, 1917-1919, undated; Series II
  This series is subdivided as follows: (a) Miscellaneous Financial Statements; (b) Progress Reports; (c) Minutes of Meetings; (d) Personnel and Organizational; (e) Research Plans; (f) Miscellaneous Papers.
  - Miscellaneous Financial Statements
    - Financial Report, 1918 January 15 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Financial Statements, 1917 October 27-1918 September (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Financial Statement, 1918 October 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Statement of Accounts [copy], 1917 October 29-1919 February 1 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      General
      Includes covering letter, unsigned, to Colonel House, 1919 March 15.
  - Progress Reports
    - Progress Report to Dec. 15, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Progress Report to Jan. 15, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      Part I, Organization; Part II, Report material on hand.
    - Douglas Johnson Mission to England and France
      - Report (from London), 1918 May 1 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Letter to Isaiah Bowman, 1918 May 9 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - [Progress] Report, 1918 May 10 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      Part I, List of work in progress; Part II, Research assignments of professional staff; Part III, Conclusions: Personnel data and financing.
    - Douglas Johnson Mission to England and France. Letter to Sidney Mezes, 1918 May 12 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - [Progress] Letter and Report, Isaiah Bowman to Colonel House, 1918 June 7 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      Summary of work in progress, details appended.
    - [Progress Report] Letter from Sidney Mezes to Colonel House, 1918 June 7 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      Enclosure: chart: Inquiry at Peace Conference.
    - [Progress Report] Letter from David Hunter Miller to Colonel House, 1918 June 17 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - [Progress Report] Letter from Walter Lippmann to Colonel House, 1918 June 13 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - [Progress Report] Letter from Isaiah Bowman to Colonel House, 1918 June 14 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      Summary of work in progress.
    - [Progress Report] Letter from Walter Lippmann to Colonel House, 1918 June 20 (Box 3, Folder 16)